<resources>
    <string name="app_name">newsreader</string>
    <string name="treetext">In botany, a tree is a perennial plant with an elongated stem, or trunk, supporting branches
        and leaves in most species. In some usages, the definition of a tree may be narrower, including only woody
        plants with secondary growth, plants that are usable as lumber or plants above a specified height. In wider
        definitions, the taller palms, tree ferns, bananas, and bamboos are also trees. Trees are not a taxonomic group
        but include a variety of plant species that have independently evolved a trunk and branches as a way to tower
        above other plants to compete for sunlight. Trees tend to be long-lived, some reaching several thousand years
        old. Trees have been in existence for 370 million years. It is estimated that there are just over 3 trillion
        mature trees in the world.[1] A tree typically has many secondary branches supported clear of the ground by the
        trunk. This trunk typically contains woody tissue for strength, and vascular tissue to carry materials from one
        part of the tree to another. For most trees it is surrounded by a layer of bark which serves as a protective
        barrier. Below the ground, the roots branch and spread out widely; they serve to anchor the tree and extract
        moisture and nutrients from the soil. Above ground, the branches divide into smaller branches and shoots. The
        shoots typically bear leaves, which capture light energy and convert it into sugars by photosynthesis, providing
        the food for the tree\'s growth and development. Trees usually reproduce using seeds. Flowers and fruit may be
        present, but some trees, such as conifers, instead have pollen cones and seed cones. Palms, bananas, and bamboos
        also produce seeds, but tree ferns produce spores instead. Trees play a significant role in reducing erosion and
        moderating the climate. They remove carbon dioxide from the atmosphere and store large quantities of carbon in
        their tissues. Trees and forests provide a habitat for many species of animals and plants. Tropical rainforests
        are among the most biodiverse habitats in the world. Trees provide shade and shelter, timber for construction,
        fuel for cooking and heating, and fruit for food as well as having many other uses. In parts of the world,
        forests are shrinking as trees are cleared to increase the amount of land available for agriculture. Because of
        their longevity and usefulness, trees have always been revered, with sacred groves in various cultures, and they
        play a role in many of the world\'s mythologies.
    </string>
    <string name="treetitle">All About Trees</string>
    <string name="flowertitle">All About Flowers</string>
    <string name="beetitle">All About Bees</string>
    <string name="cloudtitle">All About Clouds</string>
    <string name="clifftitle">All About Cliffs</string>
    <string name="cloudtext">In meteorology, a cloud is an aerosol consisting of a visible mass of minute liquid
        droplets, frozen crystals, or other particles suspended in the atmosphere of a planetary body or similar
        space.[1] Water or various other chemicals may compose the droplets and crystals. On Earth, clouds are formed as
        a result of saturation of the air when it is cooled to its dew point, or when it gains sufficient moisture
        (usually in the form of water vapor) from an adjacent source to raise the dew point to the ambient temperature.
        They are seen in the Earth\'s homosphere (which includes the troposphere, stratosphere, and mesosphere).
        Nephology is the science of clouds, which is undertaken in the cloud physics branch of meteorology. The two
        methods of naming clouds in their respective layers of the atmosphere are Latin and common. Cloud types in the
        troposphere, the atmospheric layer closest to Earth\'s surface, have Latin names due to the universal adaptation
        of Luke Howard\'s nomenclature. Formally proposed in 1802, it became the basis of a modern international system
        that divides clouds into five physical forms that appear in any or all of three altitude levels (formerly known
        as étages). These physical types, in approximate ascending order of convective activity, include stratiform
        sheets, cirriform wisps and patches, stratocumuliform layers (mainly structured as rolls, ripples, and patches),
        cumuliform heaps, and very large cumulonimbiform heaps that often show complex structures. The physical forms
        are divided by altitude level into 10 basic genus-types. Clouds reflecting in a puddle, Sutton-on-Trent, England
        The Latin names for applicable high-level genera in the troposphere carry a cirro- prefix, and an alto- prefix
        is added to the names of the mid-level genus-types. Clouds with sufficient vertical extent to occupy more than
        one altitude level are officially classified as low- or mid-level according to the altitude range at which each
        initially forms. However they are also more informally classified as multi-level or vertical, which along with
        low level clouds, do not carry any altitude related prefixes. Most of the genera can be subdivided into species
        and further subdivided into varieties. Very low stratiform clouds that extend down to the Earth\'s surface are
        given the common names fog and mist, but have no Latin names. Several clouds that form higher up in the
        stratosphere and mesosphere have common names for their main types. They are seen infrequently, mostly in the
        polar regions of Earth. Clouds have been observed in the atmospheres of other planets and moons in the Solar
        System and beyond. However, due to their different temperature characteristics, they are often composed of other
        substances such as methane, ammonia, and sulfuric acid, as well as water. The table that follows is very broad
        in scope and draws from several methods of cloud classification, both formal and informal, used in different
        levels of the Earth\'s homosphere by a number of cited authorities. They are cross-classified as a whole by form
        and level to derive the 10 tropospheric genera, the fog and mist that forms at surface level, and several
        additional major types above the troposphere. The cumulus genus includes four species that indicate vertical
        size and structure. The table should therefore be seen as an illustration of how the various cloud types are
        related to each other at all altitudes from surface-level to the \'edge of space\', rather than as a strict
        classification per se.
    </string>
    <string name="beetext">Bees are flying insects closely related to wasps and ants, known for their role in
        pollination and, in the case of the best-known bee species, the western honey bee, for producing honey and
        beeswax. Bees are a monophyletic lineage within the superfamily Apoidea and are presently considered a clade,
        called Anthophila. There are over 16,000 known species of bees in seven recognized biological families.[1][2]
        They are found on every continent except Antarctica, in every habitat on the planet that contains
        insect-pollinated flowering plants. Some species including honey bees, bumblebees, and stingless bees live
        socially in colonies. Bees are adapted for feeding on nectar and pollen, the former primarily as an energy
        source and the latter primarily for protein and other nutrients. Most pollen is used as food for larvae. Bee
        pollination is important both ecologically and commercially. The decline in wild bees has increased the value of
        pollination by commercially managed hives of honey bees. Bees range in size from tiny stingless bee species
        whose workers are less than 2 millimetres (0.08 in) long, to Megachile pluto, the largest species of leafcutter
        bee, whose females can attain a length of 39 millimetres (1.54 in). The most common bees in the Northern
        Hemisphere are the Halictidae, or sweat bees, but they are small and often mistaken for wasps or flies.
        Vertebrate predators of bees include birds such as bee-eaters; insect predators include beewolves and
        dragonflies. Human beekeeping or apiculture has been practised for millennia, since at least the times of
        Ancient Egypt and Ancient Greece. Apart from honey and pollination, honey bees produce beeswax, royal jelly and
        propolis. Bees have appeared in mythology and folklore, through all phases of art and literature, from ancient
        times to the present day, though primarily focused in the Northern Hemisphere, where beekeeping is far more
        common. The analysis of 353 wild bee and hoverfly species across Britain from 1980 to 2013 found the insects
        have been lost from a quarter of the places they inhabited in 1980.[3]
    </string>
    <string name="flowertext">A flower, sometimes known as a bloom or blossom, is the reproductive structure found in
        flowering plants (plants of the division Magnoliophyta, also called angiosperms). The biological function of a
        flower is to effect reproduction, usually by providing a mechanism for the union of sperm with eggs. Flowers may
        facilitate outcrossing (fusion of sperm and eggs from different individuals in a population) or allow selfing
        (fusion of sperm and egg from the same flower). Some flowers produce diaspores without fertilization
        (parthenocarpy). Flowers contain sporangia and are the site where gametophytes develop. Many flowers have
        evolved to be attractive to animals, so as to cause them to be vectors for the transfer of pollen. After
        fertilization, the ovary of the flower develops into fruit containing seeds. In addition to facilitating the
        reproduction of flowering plants, flowers have long been admired and used by humans to bring beauty to their
        environment, and also as objects of romance, ritual, religion, medicine and as a source of food.
    </string>
    <string name="clifftext">In geography and geology, a cliff is a vertical, or nearly vertical, rock exposure. Cliffs
        are formed as erosion landforms by the processes of weathering and erosion. Cliffs are common on coasts, in
        mountainous areas, escarpments and along rivers. Cliffs are usually formed by rock that is resistant to
        weathering and erosion. Sedimentary rocks most likely to form cliffs include sandstone, limestone, chalk, and
        dolomite. Igneous rocks such as granite and basalt also often form cliffs. An escarpment (or scarp) is a type of
        cliff, formed by the movement of a geologic fault or landslide, or by differential erosion of rock layers of
        differing hardness. Most cliffs have some form of scree slope at their base. In arid areas or under high cliffs,
        they are generally exposed jumbles of fallen rock. In areas of higher moisture, a soil slope may obscure the
        talus. Many cliffs also feature tributary waterfalls or rock shelters. Sometimes a cliff peters out at the end
        of a ridge, with tea tables or other types of rock columns remaining. Coastal erosion may lead to the formation
        of sea cliffs along a receding coastline. The Ordnance Survey distinguishes between cliffs (continuous line
        along the top edge with projections down the face) and outcrops (continuous lines along lower edge).
    </string>
</resources>
